Do you hear these weird sci-fi sounds?
Surprise.
It's actually me, Václav, speaking.
My voice is filtered using sine
wave speech, which is a technique
that radically simplifies the sound.
You might be wondering what
my voice sounds like normally.
To find out, scroll to
the bottom of this page.
When I speak, only four sine waves
are playing at any given time.
Here's what a single one sounds like.
You can actually reproduce
any sound whatsoever using a
combination of sine waves at the
right frequencies and volumes.
You would need a lot more than
four to do that well, though.
With four waves, all you get
is this R2D2-like whistling.
The thing that fascinates me the
most about sine wave speech is the
fact that after a bit of practice
and hearing the same voice before
and after, you should be able to
make out what the person is saying.
And that's despite the fact that only
minutes earlier, you thought that
these were just nonsensical whistles.
If you want to check that you
really understand the sound.
Try not looking at the subtitles.
Here, I'll play this clip again.
See, if you can understand it.